Welcome back, English learners.
My name is Marco and I am joined by Erica.
How are you, Erica?
I'm doing great Marco and you.
Excellent. I'm doing really well and I'm
really excited about our lesson for today.
That's right. We've got
an intermediate lesson
today and we're going
to study some real English.
English that you
use every day, right?
That's right. English that
native speakers really use.
Exactly. And today, as Erica
mentioned, we have an intermediate
lesson and not only is it
intermediate but it's a business lesson.
Yeah. So today we're listening
into a sales meeting and we're going
to learn some great useful
English to talk about sales strategies.
So we're going to learn
English for sales strategies for
making suggestions and for
responding to suggestions.
Great. So why don't we take a look
at our vocabulary preview for today?
Very vocabulary preview. So our vocabulary
preview is a part of our lesson when we teach
you some really important words that will
help you to understand the dialogue better.
Okay. Great. So that is
what vocabulary preview is.
We have two words for you today and we
can start off by looking at the first one.
Our first word today is
drive sales, drive sales, drive
sales to drive sales and
that means to increase sales.
Right. To sell more.
Exactly. So to drive sales.
Okay. So now let's look at
our second word and it's an
interesting one. It's promotion,
promotion, promotion.
So Erica, what is a promotion
exactly? Okay. So here we're
not really talking about
getting a better job, right?
Okay. You're not like
a job promotion. No.
We're talking about a
marketing strategy. Okay.
So I can give you an example.
Suppose that I want to buy shampoo
and if I go to the supermarket
and I see buy one and get one free.
So that's a two for one.
That's a two for one promotion. Yeah. Okay.
Okay. That's a sales promotion
or perhaps the shampoo
in the supermarket is less
expensive than usual. Okay.
Yeah. Usually maybe it
costs five dollars but today it
costs four dollars. That's
a sales promotion. Great.
So that's a really good
marketing strategy. Exactly.
And we'll hear this word
in our dialogue today.
Great. So we are ready to listen to
our dialogue. It's going to be pretty fast.
So it might be a little
bit difficult to understand.
But don't worry if you don't
understand everything because later in
this lesson, we're going to explain
all the important words and phrases.
Right people, we're holding this meeting today
because we've got to do something about our sales
and we need to do it now. I want concrete
solutions. How do you plan to drive sales? Roger.
Well, in fact, we're the
most expensive in the market.
So maybe we need to lower our
prices to match the competitors.
Lower our prices, not very
creative. It'll never fly with swan.
What kind of thinking is that, geez.
Anyone have a better plan? Natalie.
Perhaps a promotion.
Maybe a two for one offer or
something like that. That's
the same thing. Bad idea.
Really bad idea. Dammit people, come on.
Think the CEO will be here any minute.
Hello, Mr Swan. Hello, Mr Swan. Do
we have any ideas yet? Yes, Mr Swan.
We were kind of considering a two
for one offer to get more competitive.
A two for one promotion. Hmm. I kind of like the sound of
that. It sounds like something we should consider. Yeah,
exactly. That's just what I was thinking. In fact, it's a
brilliant idea. I'm glad we thought of that. Very creative.
Okay, so an interesting
manager, right?
I don't know about interesting.
Maybe I would think bad manager.
We're going to talk about
him later on in the show,
but now let's take a look
at our language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Okay, so language takeaway
is the part of our lesson where
we teach you the most
important words from the dialogue.
All these words that we are going to
focus on can be found in today's dialogue.
Exactly. So we have three words for
you today. Let's look at the first one.
Match the competitors. Match the
competitors. Match the competitors.
Great. So we have some examples
for you so you can listen and try and
see if you can figure out what
match the competitors really means.
Example one. We guarantee that we
can match the competitors' lowest price.
Example two.
It's impossible for us to match the
competitors. Our costs are just too high.
Example three.
Do you think we can match our competitors'
prices and still keep our quality high?
Okay, so I see that match
the competitors means to be as
good as or better than other
companies in the same industry.
Exactly. Match the competitors.
All right, so let's move to our
second word today for language
takeaways and it is in the market,
in the market, in the market.
We heard this phrase in the dialogue
and it means in the industry. Exactly.
I can say for example, English pod is
the best language pod in the market.
So of all the podcasts that teach
English, English pod is the best.
Of course, no doubt
about it. I totally agree.
All right, or I can give
you another example.
I pods are the most popular
MP3 players in the market.
So of all the MP3 players in the
world, I pods are the most popular.
So let's move to our final word
for today and it is, it'll never fly.
It'll never fly.
It'll never fly. It'll never fly.
So this phrase sounds a little bit strange.
I know, fly, are we talking about
an airplane here? What's going on?
Exactly, but we're not. So
we're going to give you some
examples and try and guess
what it'll never fly really means.
Example one.
This marketing plan will never fly.
It's just too expensive.
Example two.
What? You want to sell Bikini's in Alaska?
That'll never fly.
Example three.
Brad told me his idea
for film script, but the
story will never fly. It's
not interesting enough.
So it means it won't work.
It won't work. It's not a good idea.
They'll never agree.
Exactly. Great. So now we've
seen a lot of useful phrases
and we are ready to listen
to our dialogue a second time.
But this time it's going to be slow.
So you'll be able to
understand a little bit better
and you'll be able to hear
the words and phrases.
We were just talking
about all right people.
We're holding this meeting
today because we've got to
do something about our
sales and we need to do it now.
I want concrete solutions.
How do you plan to drive sales? Roger?
Well, in fact, we're the
most expensive in the market.
So maybe we need to lower our
prices to match the competitors.
Lower our prices, not very creative.
It'll never fly with swan.
What kind of thinking is that?
Jeez. Anybody else have a better plan?
Natalie?
Um, perhaps a promotion.
Maybe a two-for-one
offer or something like that.
What? That's the same thing.
Bad idea. Really bad idea.
Damn it, people. Come on.
Think the CEO will be here any minute.
Hello, Mr Swan.
Do we have any ideas yet?
Yes, Mr Swan.
We were kind of considering a
two-for-one offer to get more competitive.
A two-for-one promotion.
Hmm. I kind of like the sound of that.
It sounds like something
we should consider.
Yeah. Exactly.
That's just what I was thinking.
In fact, that's a brilliant idea.
I'm glad we thought of that very creative.
Okay, great. I hope everyone
understands a lot better now.
And I hope everyone could listen
out for some of those key words.
Right. So now it's time for us
to take a look at Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder.
So with Fluency Builder, we try
to help you increase your fluency.
We take a word or phrase
that you already know and
show you how to say it
a little bit more naturally.
A little bit more like a
native English speaker.
Right. And we have three
of these words for you today.
Yeah. Let's start with the first one.
Okay. So often students will say
something like, "I'll be here soon.
" Or, "I will arrive soon.
" Right. And these
sentences are correct.
They're totally fine, but I think
there's a better way to say this.
Right. And we heard it in the dialogue.
So let's listen to what the
person in the dialogue said.
The CEO will be here any minute.
Okay. So be here any minute.
He'll be here any minute.
It just sounds a little bit more natural.
Yeah.
I think I use this phrase quite often.
He'll be here any minute.
He'll be here soon.
Yeah. Great.
Okay. So let's move on to our
second phrase for Fluency Builder.
So this phrase will help
you to learn how to say,
"I'm thinking about something
in a better sounding way.
" Right. So you can
say something like,
"We are thinking
about a sales strategy.
" Or, that sounds like
something we should think about.
Right. And it's perfectly correct.
Yeah. There's no problem with this.
But in the dialogue, we heard
something a little bit different.
So let's listen to it.
It sounds like something
we should consider.
So consider sounds like a pretty
natural way of saying it, right?
Yeah. And, you know, I think
it sounds really kind of smart.
Yeah. It sounds more formal even.
A little more professional. Yeah. Yeah.
It's a good word. Yeah. Okay. Brilliant.
So let's move on to our third word.
Marco, you already said our third word.
Oh, yeah. I actually did. Brilliant.
That's a great word right there. Yeah.
A lot of people might say,
"That's a great idea.
" Or, "Great."
But in the dialogue, we heard
another way of saying the same idea.
That's a brilliant idea.
Okay. So this is great.
But I would have to say that
it's a little bit more British English.
Yeah. I'd agree with you there.
But I also think it sort
of gives more power to
this idea that it's a
good idea, brilliant idea.
Yeah.
It's a really, really good idea. Yeah.
Yeah. And I like that word. Yeah.
Okay. So we're ready
to listen to our dialogue
again, a third time,
but at its normal speed.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
All right, people.
We're holding this meeting today
because we've got to do something
about our sales and we need to do it now.
I want concrete solutions.
How do you plan to drive sales? Roger.
Well, in fact, we're the
most expensive in the market.
So maybe we need to lower our
prices to match the competitors.
Lower our prices, not very creative.
It'll never fly with swan.
What kind of thinking is that, Geez?
Anyone have a better plan? Natalie.
Perhaps a promotion.
Maybe a two for one
offer or something like that.
Oh, that's the same thing.
Bad idea. Really bad idea.
Dammit, people. Come on.
Think the CEO will be here any minute.
Hello, Mr. Swan.
Hello, Mr. Swan. Do we have any ideas yet?
Yes, Mr. Swan. We
were kind of considering
a two for one offer to
get more competitive.
A two for one promotion.
Hmm. I kind of like the sound of that.
It sounds like something
we should consider.
Yeah, exactly.
That's just what I was thinking.
In fact, it's a brilliant idea.
I'm glad we thought of that. Very creative.
All right, so listening to this dialogue
makes you think about this boss.
I'm pretty sure everyone has had a manager
or a supervisor that's similar to this guy.
Yeah, this boss, Clark.
I would have to say he sounds
like a terrible person to work for.
Yeah, that's true. If you're a manager,
you want to motivate your employees.
I think it's the most important thing a
manager does is to encourage his or her
employees and to help support them to
grow and to be better people in the job.
And this guy is totally not doing this.
And you can tell
because they are a little bit
scared of talking and he
cuts them off with saying,
"Oh, it's a bad idea. Give me a
better idea," and stuff like that.
Yeah, I could never
work for a guy like this.
You know, my first boss that I had
when I first entered the workforce.
I was in a very junior position and
I was working for a large company.
In the general manager of the company,
he was amazing. He was so encouraging.
He knew every single
employee's name, first name, and
he would, you know, make
an effort to stop and say,
"Hello," and ask them
how things were going.
And, you know, what this left me was
such a good feeling about the company
that I really wanted to work hard
for this company and try my best.
And I think that I've never met
such a great boss as this guy.
No, I think that's true.
Definitely, if you have a boss that's
encouraging and motivating like that,
it makes you work harder and makes
you feel part of a really special team.
And that's something
we can all agree on and
I'm sure all our managers
out there do the same.
Well, you know what? I hope some of our listeners
log on to our website and maybe they can tell us
some experiences with bad managers or good managers
or if they are managers, how they handle things.
Yeah, and hopefully they
can use some of these
great phrases that
we talked about today.
Great, so be sure everyone to visit our website
at EnglishPod.com and where you can find
a lot of other information and really good
resources to continue improving your English.
That's right, so thanks for
listening today, everyone.
And until next time, this is goodbye.
Bye.